Guide to the Randolph Brandt collection of photographs MSS.PHOTO.0535
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Randolph Brandt collection of photographs
1880-1930
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Brandt, Randolph
MSS.PHOTO.0535
0.25 Linear Feet (one half-box)
Approximately 60 prints collected by Randolph Brandt depicting transportation and other subjects in California, especially railroads and street cars.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was given to Stanford University, Special Collections by Rudolph Brandt.
Scope and Contents
Approximately 60 prints collected by Brandt depicting transportation and other subjects in California, especially railroads and street cars. Brandt contributed many images to books and magazines on the history of railroards and the San Francisco Bay Area, and the Western Neighborhoods Project's OpenSFHistory.org contains a large Emiliano Echeverria/Randolph Brandt Collection (http://opensfhistory.org/Photoset/Echeverria-Brandt_Collection). He also donated some material to Stanford's Hopkins Transportation Library, which this collection was probably part of at one time (some are stamped as such on the back). Other prints have Brandt's personal stamp "Photo from Rudolph Brandt, San Francisco" while others have handwritten "R.C. Brandt 4/10/41." The majority are good quality copy prints, with some perhaps as old as 1941, while others may be original.
Railroads -- California -- History.; California -- Description and travel -- Views.; Brandt, Randolph
- Housing [single family homes circa 1930s] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  One photograph contains a street sign named Fleming which may refer to Fleming Street in San Leandro or Fleming Avenue in Oakland or San Jose.
- Moss Beach, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Crissy Field [two men shake hands in front of U.S. Mail bi-plane, San Francisco], 1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Mountain View [billboard] (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Long Beach, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Ferries [3 prints], 1905-1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  NP Ferry circa 1930; SP Ferry circa 1930; Original Key System [illeg.] ca.1905. Handwritten on versos is "R.C. Brandt 4/10/41"
- Taber - Steamer "Mariposa", ca. 1900 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Street cars, San Diego [print & negative], ca. 1885 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Street cars San Diego [two prints] (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Street railway - San Jose [3 prints, 1 negative], ca. 1900 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Santa Cruz [pier] [2 prints], 1911, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Street cars, Santa Cruz [4 prints], ca.1899 - 1920 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Sausalito, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Ocean Shore Railway [8 prints with captions], ca. 1911-1915 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Pedro Valley, Moss Beach, Swanton, Davenport, Sharp Park
- San Francisco street cars [10 prints], 1880-1907 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Oakland, Antioch, Eastern interurban line, ca. 1918 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- California - Nevada Railroad #3 at Bryant's Station, Contra Costa County, ca. 1900 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Union Lumber Co. California, Plaster City and Fort Bragg, 1914 [2 prints] (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Northwestern Pacific Railroad - Near Pt. Reyes, ca. 1920; Howard's Occidental Station, ca. 1911 [2 prints] (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Weaverville [aerial view], 1911 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Willits, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Street Car, Nevada City, ca. 1920 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Plumas County, near Quincy Murphy Lumber Co. "Galloping Goose", ca. 1925 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Colorado Silver City New Mexico Gilpin Tramway - 2 foot gauge, ca. 1912 (Box 1, Folder 24)